[Music]
welcome back
to the next video
anyway welcome back to this next video
this one
is all about nutella so a nutella ice
cream
nutella is i mean it's massively popular
it wasn't so popular when i was growing
up it was it just
disappeared into the ether it was
available obviously
but in the last kind of 10 years it's
got this massive resurgence it's
everywhere
we always have this huge great jar of it
in the kitchen
some people eat it by the spoon
it's me too you know i'm not gonna lie
we also have
these little things little nutella put
them there so you can see them
a little nutella sweet bar things you
know like cereal bar essentially
i mean healthy i doubt it
but good all the same so
as it's international nutella day or
when this video gets released it was on
friday probably the day before we
thought we'd make a
super premium nutella ice cream so when
you look online there's lots of
nutella based ice cream recipes but
they're all
what i consider to be a little bit
oversimplified so they're
the condensed milk ice cream recipes
they're really simple
no churn there's not a lot going on
there for someone that is really into
ice cream
so this is what we're going to do today
we're going to create a super premium
ben and jerry's haagen-dazs
inspired nutella ice cream so let's just
get stuck in and make it
so to make the base for this ice cream
you're going to start by putting your
milk
and cream and the sugar in your pan on
the hob there's not a full amount of
sugar in this because a lot of sugar
comes from the actual nutella itself so
take your two very generous
tablespoons of nutella put it in that
mix while it's heating
a gentle heat just nice and gently make
sure that nutella is
well incorporated and fully dissolved
until you get that lovely creamy texture
that you can see there
at that point you can add in one and a
half tablespoons of very high quality
cocoa
then turn the heat off leave it to cool
for five six minutes something like that
then add your vanilla and finally a
pinch of salt
give it one more good stir and then take
all that put it in
a fridge safe container cover that with
cling film
and then refrigerate for at least four
hours by which time
it'll be ready to churn
so the brownie bites that's what we like
to call them in this recipe
it's just a bit of a difference in
texture really because nutella is very
creamy the ice cream is very creamy
the marshmallow swirl is very luscious
and creamy but there's nothing else in
there so by mixing these
little brownie burnt ends if you will
with the nutella you'll get little
pockets of crunchy
intense nutella flavor in this ice cream
so they're a really good addition and
this is how you make them
so as we said these brownie bites
they're made from frozen brownie burnt
ends if you will
if you don't have those you can just buy
shockboard but chop them up nice and
small keep them in the freezer
so you can turn them into a powder once
you've powdered them mix it in with some
nutella until you've got that lovely
thick paste
and then take whatever mould you're
going to use for this recipe and
spread them in make sure they're full to
the brim and pop that in the freezer
itself
the final stage of this ice cream is
going to be your marshmallow swirl which
again we've used before this is actually
a meringue
but that is exactly what ben and jerry's
using this so
put your sugar your egg whites and your
creamy tartar in the pan and heat it up
to 71 degrees that's got to be pretty
close so
if you don't have a thermometer i kind
of you know look on amazon they're
really dirt cheap
once it's at that temperature take it
off the heat and whisk it within an inch
which life for about five or six minutes
so as in a lot of my recipes 20 minutes
ago i took the ice cream base
out of the fridge and i added 75
grams of milk powder to this once you've
added it in give it a good stir
then put it back in the fridge for that
20 minutes and that will allow the milk
powder to dissolve within your base
take it out and then you're ready to
turn empty into your ice cream maker
i've had ours cooling for 10 minutes but
you don't have to do that
and then about 20 to 25 minutes later
you're going to be left with a lovely
creamy
ultra luxurious nutella ice cream so
what we're going to do now is load up
this
beautifully decorated tub again by my
wife
and we're going to layer up with ice
cream
the marshmallow and the brownie bites
the brownie bites and then keep
repeating that layer and pop in the
fridge overnight and we'll see you
tomorrow
[Music]
so it's the next day and we're gonna
take this out the tub
and see what it's like but before we do
that just a couple of minutes because i
don't want it melting everywhere
nutella is like i said it's really
really popular now it's been
movies and tv programs it's been in
friends and
friends and friends and friends
so there's a lot of product placement
for this brand or has been over the
years
but i think we're just going to take
this out the tub and really see how
good it looks now i've made this quite a
few times obviously to perfect the
recipe
so i actually know what it tastes like
but um you guys might
hopefully get excited to see it so let's
get out on top and have a look
[Music]
okay i'm actually going to put this back
in the freezer i don't want to melting
everywhere so
so there we go easy to scoop it's 24
hours
in the freezer i mean really kind of
called it fridge earlier in the freezer
really cold scoops very nicely
marshmallow looks great let's
try it see what it tastes like
bronze spoon this time let's go
a bit of everything in a bit
[Music]
the first thing is the actual ice cream
has taken on that
texture that very very luxurious silky
texture of nutella
but it's not overpoweringly so and there
i had
one of the little brownie bites and that
actually becomes a little
pocket of intense nutella flavor the
crunch
from the little you know the brownie
burnt ends for lack of a better
description
adds a really nice different kind of
texture to the to the whole thing
and the marshmallow
it is really just like a giant hug in a
tub
if you love nutella you absolutely have
to try and make this
it's incredible and you won't find this
recipe anywhere else
you'll find very boring recipes for
nutella ice cream everywhere else
so give this one a try let us know what
you think take some pictures send them
to us
and thanks for watching and we hope to
see you on the next one
take care
[Music]
that's how you celebrate that holiday